Siddaharth Suman

Software Engineer III

Objectives

Looking for a continuous learning environment and professional growth in an organization where my skills are adequately utilized.

I wish to contribute the skills that I have learned over the years for the betterment of the organization.

About Me

Software Engineer III with a total experience of 5 years and 10 months and currently working with FactSet Systems India

Self-motivated and adaptable kind of individual who yearns to get his hands on the latest trends in technology. Quick learner and a team player who is neither afraid to take lead nor afraid to ask for help in case I get stuck anywhere. Possess good communication, interpersonal, and leadership skills and can effectively deal with teammates and clients.

Experience

Dec 2018 -Present

Software Engineer III

FactSet Systems India Pvt. Ltd.

· Worked on endpoint development, data integration and creation of ui tools for the company

Dec 2015 - Dec 2018

Senior System Engineer

Infosys Ltd.

· Worked on creation of mobile and web applications as well as automating tasks.

Aug 2015 - Oct 2015

Assistant Professor

Institute of Forensic Science

· Taught the subject of Cyber Forensics and Offenses, Php and JavaScript

May 2014 - Oct 2014

Freelancer

Palmate Solutions

· Worked as a Backend Web Developer

Jan 2014 - Mar 2014

Intern

TechMeet

· Worked as an Android Application Developer

Jun 2013 - Oct 2013

Opine Solutions

· Worked as an Android Application Developer

Projects

Endpoint development Technologies: JavaScript, NodeJS | Team Size: 3

- Endpoint creation for ease of use by clients to request company's dataset and query them
- · Worked on three such endpoints and received appreciation and 2 awards

Data Importer

Technologies: Oracle SQL | Team Size: 2

· Package used to import data provided by suppliers to integrate into the company's dataset

Financial data tool

Technologies: Java, Php, WixToolset, Msi | Team Size: 5

- · Worked as acting lead on the project and ensured timely delivery of tasks and resolution of issues
- · Received award for the project

Device Management System

Technologies: React, Ionic, Angular, Php, Java, Selenium | Team Size: 1

· System for tracking and management of mobile devices

Technologies: Angular, Bulma, Typescript | Team Size: 8

· Portal for partners of the firm to be assessed on their performance and get recommendation for salary changes

Profile and Rewards Application

Assessment

Partner

Portal

Technologies: React, Bootstrap, jQuery | Team Size: 4

- · Employee centric dashboard with various reports and details of the employee
- · Employees can generate their compensation, health and time off related reports

Workspace Reservation Technologies: Android, Ionic, Cordova | Team Size: 10

- · Application for employees for reserving workspaces in their office
- · Employees can automatically get reservation when in proximity of workplace

Downloads Report Tool Technologies: Selenium, JavaFX, Apache POI, Microsoft Excel, PhantomJS | Team Size: 1

- Automation tool that generates reports for 80+ production applications
- · Reduced the time effort from 1 hour to under 5 minutes

Application **Details Portal** Technologies: Angular, Php, Servlets, Google Drive, Soap | Team Size: 1

- · Portal for internal details of applications supported by the support team
- · Includes ability for automatic healthcheck for all the applications

Buy/Sell App

Technologies: Android, Php, MySQL | Team Size: 5

· App for a buy/sell platform for company employees

Personal Info

Phone

+91 9920760964

E-mail

siddaharthsuman@gmail.com

Location

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Date of birth

December 18, 1993

Marital Status

Unmarried

Github

github.com/SiddaharthSuman

Frontend Technologies/ **Frameworks**

- JavaScript
- React
- Angular

Backend Technologies/ Frameworks

Php

Mobile Technologies

· Android

Programming Languages

Java

Testing Frameworks and Tools

Selenium

Version Control

• Git

• SVN

IDEs and Editors

Eclipse

· Visual Studio Code

Operating Systems

 Windows Linux

• Mac OS

Languages

English

Hindi

Marathi

Education

Sep 2011 - May 2015

Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai University, BE in Computer Engineering, 2015

- Conducted Training and Placement Session on "C++" for final year students
- Held the posts of Assistant Technical Head and Technical Head for Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Java Primer", "Backend Web Development" and "Android Application Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Organised Google Dev Fest for Google Developer's Group

till Mar 2011

Kendriya Vidyalaya INS Hamla, Mumbai

Publications

Feb 2015

Supercharging web applications with Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-1 Feb 2015)

Jun 2015

Information system using Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-3 June 2015)